Finding aid for the Barbara Morgan Wight Gallery Collection LSC.1872
UCLA Library Special Collections
Barbara Morgan Wight Gallery collection
1938-1967
UCLA Library Special Collections
Morgan, Barbara Brooks, 1900-1992
LSC.1872
3.2 Linear Feet (8 flat boxes)
The collection includes 143 mounted photographs, 137 of which were taken by Barbara Morgan and 6 by her husband, Willard D. Morgan. The photographs include images of dancers, nature, Camp Treetops, a Southwest series, New York cityscapes, and a junkyard series.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9968052423606533
Biography/History
Barbara Morgan was a twentieth century photographer best known for her photographs of dancers, photomontages, and light drawings. The University of California at Los Angeles Wight Gallery acquired this collection of Morgan photographs before becoming part of the Hammer Museum.
The Wight Art Gallery at University of California at Los Angeles originally opened in 1964 under the name UCLA Art Galleries and exhibited works on paper, paintings and sculpture. In 1974, the gallery is renamed to the Frederick S. Wight Art Galleries in honor of the former dean of the University of California at Los Angeles Art Department dean. Once the University of California at Los Angeles assumed control of the Armand Hammer Museum of Art and Cultural Center in 1994, the operations of the Wight Gallery were moved there and the gallery was dissolved.
Barbara Brooks Morgan was born in Buffalo, Kansas on July 8, 1900, but grew up in Los Angeles, CA. She attended UCLA from 1919 to 1923 where she trained as a painter and later joined the art faculty (1925-30). Her shift away from painting and interest in the medium of photography grew out of meeting Edward Weston.
She married Willard D. Morgan and then relocated to New York in 1930. After the birth of her two sons, Douglas (1932) and Lloyd (1935), she began to concentrate on her photography career. An accomplished designer, author, artist, and photographer, she is best known for her photographs of American modern dancers, among them, Martha Graham, Doris Humphrey, Pearl Primus, José Limón, and Charles Weidman. She contributed articles and reviews to various publications and published several books including, Martha Graham: Sixteen Dances in Photographs (1941), Summer's Children: A Photographic Cycle of Life at Camp [Camp Treetops] (1951), and A Collection of Material about Barbara Morgan (1972), as well as having a photo in Family of Man (1955). She died August 18, 1992 in Scarsdale, NY.
Scope and Content
The collection includes 143 mounted photos, 137 of which were taken by Barbara Morgan and 6 by her husband, Willard D. Morgan. These photos include photos of dancers, nature, various portraits, Camp Treetops (a children's camp featured in her book Summer's Children), a Southwest series, New York cityscapes, and a junkyard series. Examples of her experimental photomontages and photograms are also included, as are photos taken with the first Leica Model A camera by her and her husband.
Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Dance
Portraits
Nature
Experimental photographs
Auto junkyard series
Camp Treetops
Southwest series
Packing labels
Related Material
Collection 1112. Collection about Barbara Morgan, 1960-1972.
Collection 1873. Barbara Morgan Photographs, 1928-1972.
Women artists.; Women photographers -- Archives.; Morgan, Barbara Brooks, 1900-1992
- Dance., 1935-1944.
  - Valerie Bettis "Desperate Heart" (Kick) (Photomontage II)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 19" x 14 7/8" on 28" x 22" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Photomontage
  - Merce Cunningham "Leap.", Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 18 1/2" x 13 7/8" on 26" x 21" (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Merce Cunningham "Root of the Unfocus.", Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 18" on 20" x 26" (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Planned double exposure
  - Merce Cunningham "Totem Ancestor.", Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 19" x 14 1/4" on 27" x 21' (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Martha Graham "American Document" "Puritan Love Duet" with Erick Hawkins., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 18" x 15 1/4" on 27" x 22' (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Martha Graham "American Document.", Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 11 7/8" x 14 1/2" on 18 1/8" x 22' (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Trio: Sophie Maslow, Frieda Flier, Marjorie Mazia
  - Martha Graham "Celebration.", Date Taken: 1937. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 19" x 15" on 27" x 22" (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Trio: Jane Dudley, Sophie Maslow, Frieda Flier
  - Martha Graham "El Penitente" (Solo - Merce Cunningham as Christus)., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 18 1/2" x 14 1/2" on 26" x 21" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Martha Graham "Frontier.", Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 18 3/4" on 21" x 27" (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Doris Humphrey "Shakers" (Doris Humphrey-Charles Weidman Group)., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 3/8" x 14 3/4" on 20" x 21" (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Doris Humphrey "Shakers" (Solo - Beatrice Seckler) (Leap with Split)., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 15" x 18 1/8" on 22" x 26" (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Doris Humphrey "With My Red Fires" ("Matriarch")., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 14 3/4" x18 3/4" on 22" x 26" (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Doris Humphrey "With My Red Fires" ("Matriarch")., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 15 3/4" x 13 1/2" on 23" x 20" (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - José Limón "Mexican Suite" ("Conquistador" Duet - José Limón - May O'Donnell)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 16 7/8" x 14 1/4" on 25" x 21" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - José Limón "Mexican Suite" ("Indian")., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 17 3/4" x 14 3/8" on 25" x 21" (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - José Limón, "Mexican Suite" ("Peon")., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12" x 16 3/4" on 18" x 24" (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Helen Tamiris "When The Saints Come Marchin' In" (Duet with Daniel Nagrin)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 3/8" x 15 1/8" on 18" x 21" (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Charles Weidman, "On My Mother's Side.", Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 3/8" x 19 1/4" on 21" x 27" (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Charles Weidman, "Lynchtown" (Beatrice Seckler solo)., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 14 3/4" x 14 7/8" on 21" x 22" (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Asadata Dafora (Sierra Leone, Africa)., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 10 3/4" on 20" x 16" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Beaumont Newhall Leaping., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 10 5/8" on 20" x 15" (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Martha Graham, "American Document" (Trio - "We Are Three Women - We Are Three Million Women")., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 1/4" x 13 1/4" on 15" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Martha Graham, "Deep Song.", Date Taken: 1937. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 5/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Martha Graham, "Deep Song.", Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 5/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Martha Graham, "Every Soul is a Circus.", Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 5/8 x 10" on 20" x 16" (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Martha Graham, "Frontier" (Fence)., Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 1/2" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Martha Graham, "Frontier" (Running)., Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 5/8 x 13 5/8" on 17" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Martha Graham, "Frontier.", Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9 3/8" x 13 1/2" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Martha Graham, "Primitive Mysteries" (With Group)., Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 1/2" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Martha Graham, "Primitive Mysteries" (Group)., Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8 x 12 5/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Martha Graham, "Primitive Mysteries" (Group)., Date Taken: 1935..; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 13" on 14" x 19" (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Martha Graham, "Satyric Festival.", Date Taken: 1935. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 12 7/8" x 9 1/4" on 20" x 16" (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Martha Graham, "War Theme" (To Illustrate Poem by Wm Carlos Williams)., Date Taken: 1941. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10" x 13 1/8" on 15" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Erick Hawkins Jumping with Lloyd [Morgan]., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 5/8" x 9 1/2" on 15" x 19" (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Doris Humphrey, "Passacaglia.", Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1964.; Dimensions: 10 3/8" x 12 3/8" on 16" x 17" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Doris Humphrey, "Rehearsal Nightmare" (Photomontage with Doris Humphrey "Inquest" and Charles Weidman "Daddy Was A Fireman")., Date Taken: 1944..; Dimensions: 10 3/4" x 12 3/8 on 16" x 18" (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Doris Humphrey, "Square Dance" (Duet with Charles Weidman)., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 3/4" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Doris Humphrey, "To The Dance.", Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9 7/8" x 12 3/4" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Pearl Lang and Merce Cunningham "Leap.", Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 7 5/8" x 9 1/2" on 14" x 16" (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - José Limón, "Cowboy Song," photomontage., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 11 1/2" x 9 3/4" on 19" x 15" (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Pearl Primus, "Speak To Me Of Rivers.", Date Taken: 1944..; Dimensions: 10 1/4" x 13 1/4" on 16" x 20" (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Charles Weidman, "Daddy Was A Fireman" (Duet with Peter Hamilton)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 1/4" x 10 1/2" on 20" x 16" (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hanya Holm, "Trend" (I)., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 5 3/4" x 9 3/4" on 12" x 15" (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hanya Holm, "Trend" (II)., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 5 3/8" x 9 7/16" on 12" x 15" (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Portraits., 1940-1958.
  - Nancy Newhall., Date Taken: 1942..; Dimensions: 5" x 5 5/8" on 12" x 11" (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Beaumont Newhall., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 3/8" x 11 7/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Charles Sheeler and His Favorite Beech Tree., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 1/2" x 10 1/8" on 18" x 14" (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cradled., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 5/8" x 10 5/8" on 21" x 16" (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Daisetz [Teitaro] Suzuki., Date Taken: 1958..; Dimensions: 12" x 7 1/8" on 18 1/4" x 14" (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki at Work (New York Study)., Date Taken: 1958. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 10 1/2" on 20" x 16" (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gerald Heard., Date Taken: 1954. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 1/2" x 12 7/8" on 16" x 19" (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Le Corbusier In New York., Date Taken: 1946. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 1/2" x 12 1/8" on 17" x 18" (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Marie., Date Taken: 1947. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 9/16" x 10" on 20" x 15" (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Professor Joseph Campbell & Student, Sarah Lawrence College., Date Taken: ca. 1953. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 9 5/8" x 12" on 14 1/8" x 18" (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Willard Tossing Cats., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 7 5/8" x 13 1/4" on 14" x 19" (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Man's Knee., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 12 3/4" x 10" on 10" x 16" (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Willard's Fist (Strobe)., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 1/8" x 10 3/4" on 18' x 20" (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Woman's Hand., Date Taken: 1950. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 1/4" x 11 3/8 on 16" x 19" (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Ansel Adams Jumping on Stool (In BarbaraMorgan's Studio)., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 5/8" x 14 7/8" on 18" x 21" (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lloyd's Head., Date Taken: 1945..; Dimensions: 15 1/4" x 10 7/8" on 22" x 17" (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pregnant., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 16 1/4" x 12 3/8" on 24" x 19" (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Beaumont Newhall, Ansel Adams and Willard Morgan (In Barbara Morgan's Studio)., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1976.; Dimensions: 14 78" x 17 3/4" on 22" x 25" (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Nature., 1937-1970.
  - Two Trees., Date Taken: 1950. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9 1/8" x 7 5/8" on 14" x 12" (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Amaryllis Seed Pod., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 11 5/8" on 18" x 19" (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Beech Tree II., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 11 7/8" x 16 1/2" on 18" x 23" (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Beech Tree XIV., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 14 3/4" x 14 3/4" on 22" x 21" (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Photomontage - Strobe
  - Begonia Leaf., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 12" x 16 3/8" on 19" x 23" (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Macro
  - Delicate Beech., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 14 7/8" x 13 7/8" on 23" x 20" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Solstice (Ice on Window Series)., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 16 1/2" x 11 1/4" on 24" x 18" (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Sumach Leaves, In and Out of Focus., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 1/4" x 15" on 18" x 21" (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Beech Tree VI (Luke Estate - Irvington NY)., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 12 3/4" x 9 1/4" on 18" x 14" (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Beech Tree XI., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 12 1/4" x 7 1/4" on 18" x 13" (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Caterpiller Beech., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 3/8" x 10 3/8" on 16" x 16" (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Dawn Window., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 7 5/8" x 13 1/8" on 14" x 19" (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ice On Window., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 13 5/8" x 10 1/4" on 20" x 16" (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ice On Window II., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 3/4" x 9 3/4" on 20" x 16" (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ice On Window, SAETA., Date Taken: 1942. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9 5/8" x 11 7/8" on 16" x 17 3/4 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Mud and Ice (High Point Road Scarsdale)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 3/8" x 13 5/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Planet On Fire., Date Taken: 1971. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 11 7/8" x 10" on 20" x 14" (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Stump., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 12 7/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Tossed Cats., Date Taken: 1942..; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 1/2 on 16" x 20" (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Strobe
  - Tree Trunk., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 5/8" x 10 1/8" on 20" x 15" (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Walnut., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 13 1/2" on 16" x 20" (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Wild Bee Honeycomb., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 9172.; Dimensions: 7 3/8" x 7 7/16 on 16" x 14" (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Experimental photographs., 1938-1970.
  - Briarlock., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 13 7/8" x 13 3/8" on 21" x 19" (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fossil in Formation., Date Taken: 1965. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 1/2" x 16 5/8" on 19" x 23" (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Light Echoes., Date Taken: 1970. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 15 3/4" on 16" x 22" (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Photogram
  - Trajectory., Date Taken: 1946. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 17 1/2" x 12" on 24" x 17" (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Changing Grid., Date Taken: 1970. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 19 3/4" x 15 1/2" on 26" x 19" (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Serial Photogram
  - Continuum II (Leaves)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 15 5/8" x 1 5/8" on 22"x 27" (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ikons in Time-Stream (Photomontage - Ishtar 3000 B.C. and Empire State Blgd)., Date Taken: 1963. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13" x 17 1/2" on 19" x 25" (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Photo - Nature - Photomontage
  - Orbiting., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 18 7/8" x 12" on 26" x 19" (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Light Drawing
  - Broken Light Bulb., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 3/8" x 9 1/2" on 20" x 16" (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - City Shell., Date Taken: 1938. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 9 5/8" on 19 3/4" x 15 3/4" (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - City Sound (New York)., Date Taken: 1937. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 3/8" x 8 7/8" on 20" x 15" (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - City Street., Date Taken: 1937. Date Printed: 1964.; Dimensions: 13 1/4" x 10" on 18" x 15" (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Corn Leaf Rhythm., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 14" x 19 1/2" on 16" x 19 1/2" (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Corn Tassel Through Broken Windshield., Date Taken: 1967. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 11 5/8" x 10 3/4" on 15" x 18" (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Photogram - Photomontage
  - Currents., Date Taken: 1972..; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 10 7/16" on 16" x 20" (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fence., Date Taken: 1970. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 3/4" x 9 3/4" on 15" x 20" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Funkia Leaf., Date Taken: 1950. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 3/8" x 11" on 20" x 16" (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Solarized
  - Light Waves., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 13 1/2" on 15 1/2 " x 18 1/8" (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Serpent Light (Light Dressing)., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 9 1/4" x 12" on 16" x 18" (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Striation I., Date Taken: 1972. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13" x 19 3/4" on 15" x 20" (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Auto Junkyard Series., 1940-1947.
  - Auto Crash., Date Taken: 1947. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 11 7/8" x 10" on 19" x 16" (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ghost of The Crash., Date Taken: 1947. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 11 1/4" x 10 5/8" on 18" x 16" (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Resurrection in the Junkyard., Date Taken: 1947. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 10 1/4" x 13 1/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Camp Treetops (Summer's Children)., 1940-1948.
  - Boy and Hamster, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 5 1/4" 6 12" x 11" x 11" (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Boy with Frog, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 4 1/2" x 10 1/2" on 15" x 10" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Boy with Snake (from "Summer's Children" by Barbara Morgan Pub. Morgan & Morgan)., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 7" x 6 1/8" on 12" x 11" (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Girl and Ring of Water, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 7 1/4" x 9 5/8" on 12" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Girl with Goat, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 7 7/8" x 9 3/4" on 14" x 12" (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Girl with Snake, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9"x 6 1/2" on 14" x 12" (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Three Buddies, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1946. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 6 7/8" x 9 3/8" on 13" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Two Boys and Snake, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 6 1/2" x 9 3/8" on 12" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bedtime Story, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1947. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 17 1/2" x 13 7/8" on 20" x 24" (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Bear Hugging, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1947. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 12 3/4" on 16" x 20" (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bee Sting, Camp Treetops (from "Summer's Children")., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 10" x 12 1/8" on 15" x 18" (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Boy and Goat, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 10 1/8" x 11 3/8" on 14" x 16" (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Boy Sharpening Axe, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 1/8" x 9" on 20" x 15" (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Boy with Visor, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 5/8" x 10 5/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Brothers (Lloyd and Doug [Morgan]), Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 1/4" x 10 1/2" on 16" x 20' (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Barbara Morgan's sons
  - Children Dancing By Lake, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 11 1/4" x 16" on 17" x 21" (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Diving off the Dock, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1946. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9 5/8" x 13 1/8" on 16" x 20" (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Doug [Morgan] in Rafters, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1943..; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 10 1/2" on 19" x 16" (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Doug [Morgan] with Chicken, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1943. Date Printed: 1970.; Dimensions: 9 1/4" x 7 1/4" on 15" x 12 1/2" (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Girl Playing Recorder, Camp Treetops (From book "Summer's Children" A Photograph Cycle of Light Camp; als in "Family of Man" MOMA - NYC., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 13 3/8" x 9 3/4" on 20" x 16" (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Girl Sewing, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 1/2" x 13 1/2" on 16" x 20" (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Girls Dancing By Lake, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 13 1/2" x 10 3/4" on 20" x 16" (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Goat Begging, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1948. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 5/8" x 10 1/4" on 18" x 15" (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hand Stands, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1940. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 12 5/8" x 7 1/2" on 18" x 14" (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Our Own House, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1944. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 10 1/2" x 12 1/4" on 16" x 19" (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Out to Pasture, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1946. Date Printed: 1971.; Dimensions: 9" x 12 7/8" on 16" x 18" (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sand Builders, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1945. Date Printed: 1945.; Dimensions: 8 5/8" x 11 3/4" on 19" x 17" (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Singing in the Rain, Camp Treetops., Date Taken: 1950. Date Printed: 1969.; Dimensions: 9" x 11 1/8" on 15" x 17" (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Southwest Series., 1928-1929.
  - Barbara Morgan Cooking in Canyon de Chelly., Date Taken: 1928..; Dimensions: 6 7/8" x 9 3/8" on 11" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Photo by Willard Morgan
  - Barbara Morgan in Grand Canyon., Date Taken: 1928. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 6 3/4" on 15" x 12" (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Photo by Willard D Morgan
  - Carreta de Meurto, El Penitente Morado, Trampas, NM., Date Taken: 1928..; Dimensions: 7 3/4" x 8 1/2" on 11" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hopi Indian., Date Taken: 1928..; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 6 1/8" on 14" x 11" (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Photo by Willard D Morgan, taken with Leica Model A
  - Hopi Indian with Ceremonial Eagle., Date Taken: 1928..; Dimensions: 9 1/2" x 6 1/4" on 14" x 11" (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mono Lake, California., Date Taken: 1929..; Dimensions: 6 3/8" x 9 1/2" on 11" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sand Slide Mono Lake., Date Taken: 1929..; Dimensions: 6 1/4" x 9 1/2" on 11" x 14" (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Photo taken with Leica Model A
  - Willard Morgan Descending into Canyon de Chelly., Date Taken: 1928. Date Printed: 1972.; Dimensions: 8 3/8" x 12 1/4" on 14" x 18" (Box 8, Folder 19)